Guide to the David A. Edwards papers, 1970-2011
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
David A. Edwards papers
1970-2011
C0192
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
2.75 linear feet (6 boxes)
This collection contains correspondence, reports, newsclippings, budgets, and some papers from the Reston Board of Commerce and the Reston Chamber of Commerce, as well as general Reston and Dulles corridor planning documents from Edwards' professional career and his involvement in community activities from 1970-2011.
Edwards, David A.
Scope and Content
The David A. Edwards collection largely contains correspondence, meeting minutes, and reports on transportation and zoning in Reston. Most files are related to the Reston Board of Commerce, the Reston Chamber of Commerce, and various Reston community associations. There are also files on Metro extension in the Dulles corridor, and other transporation initiatives.
Series 1 contains information about Reston, Virginia. Mostly, this series is comprised of documents generated by the Reston Board of Commerce, the Reston Chamber of Commerce, and various subcommittes, including the Reston Transportation Committee. In addition to transportation, Reston Town Center planning and development and new Reston subdivisions are focal points in this series. This series is arranged alphabetically.
Series 2 contains documents about the Dulles Corridor extension, as well as general transportation and planning papers regarding Northern Virginia. The Dulles Toll Road, mass transit in Northen Virginia, transportation costs, and proposed ideas to generate revenue for new roads and an expanded metro line to Dulles Airport. This series is arranged alphabetically.
Series 3 consists of 1 compact disc with 5,179 electronic files on transportation and planning in Northern Virginia, particularly Reston and the Dulles Corridor. There are also files that document the activities of the Reston Planning and Zoning Committee.
Biographical Information
David A. Edwards moved to Reston in 1967, where he spent most of his professional career in city and regional planning. Edwards became Deputy Director of the Fairfax County Economic Development Authority in 1970, and in 1973 he was promoted to Director. From 1985 until he retired in 2002, Edwards was Manager of Area Development at Washington Gas.
Related Materials
Special Collections and Archives holds numerous other collections related to Reston, Virginia.
Arrangement
Organized into two series.
Series 1: Reston, 1970-2011 (Boxes 1-3)
Series 2: Dulles Corridor, 1970-2011 (Boxes 4-6)
Series 3: Electronic Files, 2010-2011 (Box 6)
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Loren Bruce in 2011.
Index Terms
Persons:
Edwards, David A.
Geographical Names:
Dulles Toll Road (Va.); Reston (Va.)
Subjects:
Transportation--Washington Metropolitan Area--Planning.
Contents List
- Series 1: Reston, 1970-2011; (3 boxes)
  Series 1 contains information about Reston, Virginia. Mostly, this series is comprised of documents generated by the Reston Board of Commerce, the Reston Chamber of Commerce, and various subcommittees, including the Reston Transportation Committee.
  - A Public Art Master Plan for Reston, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Additional Potomac River Crossings, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Best of Reston Awards, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brownbuilder, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Contemporary Homes in Reston, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dix, Bob, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Edwards, David A., 1937-2011 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Forecast for the Reston/Dulles Rail Corridor, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Greater Reston Business to Business Directory, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Greater Reston Chamber of Commerce Transportation and Government Affairs Committee, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Greater Reston Chamber of Commerce Transportation Committee, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hunter Woods Rezoning, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Members of the GRCC Transportation and Government Affairs Committee, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - News From Reston, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Newsclippings About Reston, 1970-1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Open Space Study, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Request for Technical Studies Grant, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Reston Association Newsletters, 1984-2002 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Reston Board of Commerce, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Reston Board of Commerce, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Reston Board of Commerce, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Reston Board of Commerce, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Reston Board of Commerce, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Reston Chamber of Commerce (GRCC), 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Reston Chamber of Commerce (GRCC), 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Reston Chamber of Commerce (GRCC), 1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Reston Chamber of Commerce Human Services Committee, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Reston Community Associations, 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Reston Golf and Country Club, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Reston Handbook, 1986; 1990 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Reston Histories, 1970-1971; 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Reston Homeowners Association, 1967-1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Reston Land Corporation, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Reston Maps, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Reston Neighborhoods, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Reston Real Estate and Communities, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Reston Real Estate and Communities, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Reston Town Center, 1980-1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Reston Transit Station Parking, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Reston Transportation Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Reston Transportation Committee, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Reston Transportation Committee, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Reston Transportation Committee, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Reston Transportation Committee, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Reston Transportation Committee, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Reston Transportation Committee, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Reston Transportation Committee, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Reston Transportation Committee, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Reston Transportation Committee, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Restructuring the Reston Transportation Committee, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Space Station Headquarters, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - The Life and Times of Reston, Virginia, 2000s (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Series 2: Dulles Corridor, 1970-2011; (3 boxes)
  Series 2 contains documents about the Dulles Corridor extension, as well as general transportation and planning papers regarding Northern Virginia.
  - Accessible Hospitals in NOVA, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bus Transit in the Dulles Corridor, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Committee for Dulles, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Commonwealth Transportation Alliance, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - County of Fairfax Board of Supervisors, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dart Rail Mass Transit Plan, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dulles Corridor Bus Tour, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dulles Corridor Rapid Transportation Studies, 1990-2000 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dulles Corridor Task Force, 1993-2000 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Dulles Corridor Task Force Preliminary Report, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Dulles Corridor Transportation Seminar, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Dulles Greenway, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Dulles Greenway, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Dulles Toll Road Extension, 1988-1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dulles Toll Road Extension, 1988-1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Dulles Toll Road, Fairfax County, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Efforts to Amend the Constrained Long-Range Transportation Plan, 1997-2002 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Fairfax Chamber of Commerce Joint Task Force, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Fastoll Statistics, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Maryland Options to Raise Tax Revenue for Transportation, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Mass Transit in the Dulles Corridor, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Northern Virginia Transportation Alliance, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Northern Virginia Transportation Compact, 2002-2003 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - NOVA Transportation Bond Funding HB1990, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Rail Transit in the Dulles Corridor, 1990-1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Regional Transportation Projects and Priorities, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Sales Tax Referendum, 1990s (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Transportation Costs and "Sprawl", 2000 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Transportation Funding in Northern Virginia, 1995-2001 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Transportation Funding Allocation Formula, 1990s (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Series 3: Electronic Files, 2010-2011
  1 compact disc with 5,179 electronic files on transportation and planning in Northern Virginia, particularly Reston and the Dulles Corridor. There are also files that document the activities of the Reston Planning and Zoning Committee.